<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<data>
	<node>
		<title><![CDATA[The Difference Between a Resume and a Curriculum Vitae]]></title>
		<short_description><![CDATA[What is the difference between a resume and a CV? The primary differences between a resume and a curriculum vitae (CV) are length, what is included, and what each is used for. While both are used in job applications, a resume and a CV are not always interchangeable.]]></short_description>
		<org_url><![CDATA[https://www.thebalancecareers.com/cv-vs-resume-2058495]]></org_url>
		<tag><![CDATA[CV]]></tag>
		<membership><![CDATA[Free,Silver,Gold]]></membership>
		<categories><![CDATA[level1]]></categories>
	</node>
	<node>
		<title><![CDATA[Learn How to Format Your CV]]></title>
		<short_description><![CDATA[In the tech industry, a curriculum vitae, or CV, may be used instead of a resume for professionals in academia or research. A CV may also be used by technology professionals that are in certain industries, such as medicine or bioinformatics. A CV or curriculum vitae is most commonly used outside of the U.S. I have also seen many US-based Ph.D. graduates use a short CV instead of a resume.]]></short_description>
		<org_url><![CDATA[https://www.thebalancecareers.com/examples-of-cv-format-sections-2071803]]></org_url>
		<tag><![CDATA[CV]]></tag>
		<membership><![CDATA[Free,Silver,Gold]]></membership>
		<categories><![CDATA[level1]]></categories>
	</node>
	<node>
		<title><![CDATA[Curriculum Vitae (CV) Samples and Writing Tips]]></title>
		<short_description><![CDATA[When applying for certain positions in the US, as well as jobs internationally, you may be required to submit a curriculum vitae rather than a resume. A curriculum vitae, or CV, includes more information than your typical resume, including details of your education and academic achievements, research, publications, awards, affiliations, and more.

Here you can review curriculum vitae samples, learn about the difference between a CV and a resume, and glean tips and advice on how to write a CV.]]></short_description>
		<org_url><![CDATA[https://www.thebalancecareers.com/cv-samples-and-writing-tips-2060349]]></org_url>
		<tag><![CDATA[CV]]></tag>
		<membership><![CDATA[Silver,Gold]]></membership>
		<categories><![CDATA[level2]]></categories>
	</node>
	<node>
		<title><![CDATA[Formatting Tips for Your Curriculum Vitae]]></title>
		<short_description><![CDATA[Do you need to write a curriculum vitae? A curriculum vitae, commonly known as a CV, is an alternative to writing a resume to apply for a job. CVs are most commonly used in academia, research and medicine – not to mention for most jobs outside of the United States.]]></short_description>
		<org_url><![CDATA[https://www.thebalancecareers.com/curriculum-vitae-format-2060351]]></org_url>
		<tag><![CDATA[CV]]></tag>
		<membership><![CDATA[Silver,Gold]]></membership>
		<categories><![CDATA[level2]]></categories>
	</node>
	<node>
		<title><![CDATA[Academic Curriculum Vitae (CV) Example and Writing Tips]]></title>
		<short_description><![CDATA[A curriculum vitae (CV) written for academia should highlight research and teaching experience, publications, grants and fellowships, professional associations and licenses, awards, and any other details in your experience that show you’re the best candidate for a faculty or research position advertised by a college or university.]]></short_description>
		<org_url><![CDATA[https://www.thebalancecareers.com/academic-curriculum-vitae-example-2060817]]></org_url>
		<tag><![CDATA[CV]]></tag>
		<membership><![CDATA[Gold]]></membership>
		<categories><![CDATA[level3]]></categories>
	</node>
	<node>
		<title><![CDATA[How to Write a CV as a Technical Academic]]></title>
		<short_description><![CDATA[IT and related skills areas continue to become a burgeoning area of study in the US. To secure a job in the academy, craft a skills-focused CV that highlights proficient expertise in your area. CV formats vary, but starting with career objectives, and drawing attention to skills and experience from the outset will work in your favor. Here are guidelines and a sample CV for a technical academic.]]></short_description>
		<org_url><![CDATA[https://www.thebalancecareers.com/how-to-write-a-cv-as-a-technical-academic-2071809]]></org_url>
		<tag><![CDATA[CV]]></tag>
		<membership><![CDATA[Gold]]></membership>
		<categories><![CDATA[level3]]></categories>
	</node>
	<node>
		<title><![CDATA[Cover Letter Examples for Students and Recent Graduates]]></title>
		<short_description><![CDATA[The following cover letters and cover letter templates are designed especially for high school students, as well as for college students and recent graduates seeking employment.]]></short_description>
		<org_url><![CDATA[https://www.thebalancecareers.com/student-cover-letter-samples-2063664]]></org_url>
		<tag><![CDATA[cover letter]]></tag>
		<membership><![CDATA[Free,Silver,Gold]]></membership>
		<categories><![CDATA[level1]]></categories>
	</node>
	<node>
		<title><![CDATA[Entry-Level Cover Letter Examples and Writing Tips]]></title>
		<short_description><![CDATA[When you are applying for an entry-level position, composing a cover letter can be a challenge because you may not have a lot of work experience. However, it's fine to highlight your non-employment related experience in your cover letter if it's relevant to the job. After all, interviewers for entry-level positions are aware that this may be your first position.]]></short_description>
		<org_url><![CDATA[https://www.thebalancecareers.com/entry-level-cover-letter-examples-2063809]]></org_url>
		<tag><![CDATA[cover letter]]></tag>
		<membership><![CDATA[Free,Silver,Gold]]></membership>
		<categories><![CDATA[level1]]></categories>
	</node>
	<node>
		<title><![CDATA[How to Format a Cover Letter With Examples]]></title>
		<short_description><![CDATA[When you are applying for a job, how you format your cover letter is important because the letter is one of the first impressions you'll make on an employer. In fact, how you format your letter is almost as important as what you write in it. A cover letter that is formatted incorrectly, or is difficult to read, can quickly eliminate you from the pool of candidates, so it's critical to pay just as much attention to the formatting of your letter as to its content.]]></short_description>
		<org_url><![CDATA[https://www.thebalancecareers.com/cover-letter-format-2060205]]></org_url>
		<tag><![CDATA[cover letter]]></tag>
		<membership><![CDATA[Silver,Gold]]></membership>
		<categories><![CDATA[level2]]></categories>
	</node>
	<node>
		<title><![CDATA[Cover Letter Example - eCommerce Technology]]></title>
		<short_description><![CDATA[The following is an example of a cover letter for a job in eCommerce technology. Specifically, the letter is for a job as Associate Vice President of eCommerce Technology.]]></short_description>
		<org_url><![CDATA[https://www.thebalancecareers.com/cover-letter-example-ecommerce-technology-2060218]]></org_url>
		<tag><![CDATA[cover letter]]></tag>
		<membership><![CDATA[Silver,Gold]]></membership>
		<categories><![CDATA[level2]]></categories>
	</node>
	<node>
		<title><![CDATA[100+ Free Professional Cover Letter Examples]]></title>
		<short_description><![CDATA[Do you need to write a cover letter? When applying for a job, a cover letter should be sent or posted with your resume or curriculum vitae. A cover letter is a (typically) one-page document that explains to the hiring manager why you are an ideal candidate for the job. It goes beyond your resume to explain in detail how you could add value to the company.]]></short_description>
		<org_url><![CDATA[https://www.thebalancecareers.com/free-cover-letter-examples-and-writing-tips-2060208]]></org_url>
		<tag><![CDATA[cover letter]]></tag>
		<membership><![CDATA[Gold]]></membership>
		<categories><![CDATA[level3]]></categories>
	</node>
	<node>
		<title><![CDATA[Free Cover Letter Templates for Job Applications]]></title>
		<short_description><![CDATA[When you're writing a cover letter, the layout and format of your cover letter are important. A cover letter template can help you format, layout, and design a professional cover letter.

You shouldn't have to pay for a cover letter template. There are plenty of free, reliable templates available online.]]></short_description>
		<org_url><![CDATA[https://www.thebalancecareers.com/free-cover-letter-templates-2060194]]></org_url>
		<tag><![CDATA[cover letter]]></tag>
		<membership><![CDATA[Gold]]></membership>
		<categories><![CDATA[level3]]></categories>
	</node>
	<node>
		<title><![CDATA[What to Expect During a Job Interview]]></title>
		<short_description><![CDATA[Whether you are in high school, college, a recent college graduate, or you have been out of the workforce, your job interview does not have to be an intimidating experience. An interview is an opportunity for both you and the employer to decide whether or not you are a good fit.]]></short_description>
		<org_url><![CDATA[https://www.thebalancecareers.com/what-to-expect-during-a-job-interview-2063897]]></org_url>
		<tag><![CDATA[interview]]></tag>
		<membership><![CDATA[Free,Silver,Gold]]></membership>
		<categories><![CDATA[level1]]></categories>
	</node>
	<node>
		<title><![CDATA[Get Some Great Phone Interview Tips]]></title>
		<short_description><![CDATA[While you're job searching, it's important to be prepared for a phone interview on a moment's notice. Many companies start the interview process with a phone call to discuss the job opportunity with a prospective employee, determine if the candidate is a good fit, and to gauge his or her interest in the position.]]></short_description>
		<org_url><![CDATA[https://www.thebalancecareers.com/how-to-ace-a-phone-interview-2058579]]></org_url>
		<tag><![CDATA[interview]]></tag>
		<membership><![CDATA[Free,Silver,Gold]]></membership>
		<categories><![CDATA[level1]]></categories>
	</node>
	<node>
		<title><![CDATA[7 Interview Tips That Will Help You Get Hired]]></title>
		<short_description><![CDATA[Even when you have gone on more interviews than you can count, job interviewing never seems to get any easier. With each job interview, you are meeting new people, selling yourself and your skills, and often getting the third degree about what you know or don't know. And, you need to stay upbeat and enthusiastic through it all. This can be a challenge, especially when you're interviewing for a job you would love to get hired for.]]></short_description>
		<org_url><![CDATA[https://www.thebalancecareers.com/top-interview-tips-2058577]]></org_url>
		<tag><![CDATA[interview]]></tag>
		<membership><![CDATA[Silver,Gold]]></membership>
		<categories><![CDATA[level2]]></categories>
	</node>
	<node>
		<title><![CDATA[Group Interview Questions and Interviewing Tips]]></title>
		<short_description><![CDATA[There are two types of group interviews, and your experience will vary depending on which one you're participating in. Both can be challenging for candidates. Find out more about the kinds of group interviews that take place, what questions to expect, and how you can shine during this type of interview.  ]]></short_description>
		<org_url><![CDATA[https://www.thebalancecareers.com/group-interview-questions-and-interviewing-tips-2061157]]></org_url>
		<tag><![CDATA[interview]]></tag>
		<membership><![CDATA[Silver,Gold]]></membership>
		<categories><![CDATA[level2]]></categories>
	</node>
	<node>
		<title><![CDATA[Types of Job Interview Questions]]></title>
		<short_description><![CDATA[When you go on a job interview, there are a variety of different types of interview questions you'll be asked. Interviews may ask behavioral, case, situational, or competency-based questions. You'll also be asked about your employment history, your ability to work on a team, your leadership skills, your motivation, as well as other interview questions related to your skills and abilities.]]></short_description>
		<org_url><![CDATA[https://www.thebalancecareers.com/types-of-interview-questions-2061365]]></org_url>
		<tag><![CDATA[interview]]></tag>
		<membership><![CDATA[Gold]]></membership>
		<categories><![CDATA[level3]]></categories>
	</node>
	<node>
		<title><![CDATA[Best Techniques for a Successful Job Interview]]></title>
		<short_description><![CDATA[When you're interviewing for a job, the little things can make a big difference. Even a small mistake can cost you a job offer. Take the time to prepare so you can make the best possible impression at every job interview you go on.]]></short_description>
		<org_url><![CDATA[https://www.thebalancecareers.com/top-job-interview-tips-2061331]]></org_url>
		<tag><![CDATA[interview]]></tag>
		<membership><![CDATA[Gold]]></membership>
		<categories><![CDATA[level3]]></categories>
	</node>
</data>
